<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>🖐🏻 Handscribe: A Gloss-Free Framework for Sign Language Translation and Gloss Sequence Generation 🤌🏻</title>
    <link href="/handscribe/"/>
    <url>/handscribe/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sign language translation systems traditionally rely on intermediate gloss representations to bridge the gap between visual input and written language output. However, manual gloss annotation is costly, language-dependent, and often lossy, prompting growing interest in gloss-free alternatives. This paper introduces Handscribe, a novel two-stage framework for gloss-free sign language translation and gloss sequence generation. Handscribe first translates continuous sign language videos into written language sentences using a lightweight decoder built atop SlowFast-based spatiotemporal features and a frozen mBART model. Then, in the second stage, it generates gloss sequences from these sentences using a Large Language Model (LLaMa3.1-8B-Instruct) that has been fine-tuned with weak supervision. Our experiments on PHOENIX-2014-T and Wav2Gloss Fieldwork demonstrate strong translation performance and state-of-the-art multilingual gloss generation, even in zero-shot settings. The proposed framework reduces annotation bottlenecks while maintaining flexibility and interpretability, paving the way for scalable and inclusive sign language technologies.</p><p><img src="/../img/Handscribe_Architecture.png"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Sign Language Translation, SlowFast Network, Large Language Models, Accessibility Technologies</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Instructing and Prompting Large Language Models for Explainable Cross-domain Recommendations 🎥💿📚</title>
    <link href="/instructing_llms/"/>
    <url>/instructing_llms/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We present a method for using large language models (LLMs) to provide explainable cross-domain recommendations despite data scarcity. It involves instructing an LLM, creating personalized prompts, and processing responses to generate and explain recommendations. Experimental results show this approach outperforms existing methods.</p><p><img src="/../img/recsys.png"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Recommender System, Cross Domain Recommendation, Large Language Models</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>🖼️ Art2Mus: Bridging Visual Arts and Music through Cross-Modal Generation 🎵</title>
    <link href="/art2mus/"/>
    <url>/art2mus/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Artificial Intelligence has transformed music creation by using generative models that respond to textual or visual prompts. Current image-to-music models are limited to basic images, unable to handle complex digital artworks. To address this gap, we propose Art2Mus, a novel model designed to create music from digitized artworks or text inputs. Art2Mus extends the AudioLDM 2 architecture, a text-to-audio model, and employs our newly curated datasets, created via ImageBind, which pair digitized artworks with music. Experimental results show that Art2Mus generates music that resonates with the input stimuli, suggesting potential applications in multimedia art, interactive installations, and AI-driven creative tools.</p><p><img src="/../img/Art2Mus_Architecture.png"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Generative AI, Conditioned Music Generation, Multimodal Deep Learning</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
